

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Technical Architecture, Requirement Gathering, Agile Methodology, Project Management, MySQL, Java, Spring Boot



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 8 Month(s)

Current Company: Wipro Limited Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication] Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Technical Architecture, Requirement Gathering, Agile Methodology, Project Management, MySQL, Java, Spring Boot

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Summary

Senior Software Engineer with 5+ years of industry experience, looking for opportunities to create value. From the beginning of my career I have been a great team player and a committed individual contributor. I have a passion for problem solving and creating high quality software products.

Work Experience

Wipro Limited as Senior Software Engineer May 2019 to Till Date

- I am working as java developer for the migration application and responsible for completing the assigned stories within estimated timeline.
- I have worked as java developer with technologies Java 8, Spring Boot, Restful webservice, Couch DB, Collections.
- Involved in building the migration code from mongo dB to couchdB. Written multiple views and queries in couch db for data management and processing.
- Implemented different parsing scenarios required for tibo projects using java 8, spring boot framework.
- Performed end to end testing of the project using different technologies like tibco, couchdb and fuse xml.
- Implemented rest web service and provided endpoints with required services.
- Designing technical design document and process documents for developed application.

Softvision Cognizant as Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2015 to May 2019

CURRENT AND PREVIOUS PROJECTS

Project Name: Mst Eps Credit Auth Migration*

Client: Macys Team Size: 10

Duration : 10 Months

Environment: Java8, Spring Boot, WebServices-SOAP & REST, SAAJ Client, Logback, Eclipse, SonarQube, FishEye,

Git. Jira tool.

Description: Basically this project is built to replace the legacy Mainframe business flow into SCMCredit application using Java & Webservices. This new business logic is to provide stable and efficient way for the clients which deployed over

many stores to remove dependency over mainframe application. As a part of the development, we are developing a complete new application called SCMCredit which takes SOAP request from EPS(EnterprisePaymentService) and processes the request based on some business logic. This will interact with Vantive server to get the required response and provides back the response based on the different Authorization types to the client. Also, this application incorporates Encryption/Decryption of Account Number using EES service for the security.

Responsibilities:

Involved in building the SCMCredit application different fields based on requirement documentation.

Based on the business requirements creating the Vantiv response fields for specified Authorization type.

Implemented mock rest response for vantiv server.

Involved in writing Junit test cases for the SCMCredit application.

Code cleanup activity using SonarQube. Reduced the Major/Minor warnings in the code.

Identified and fixed some of bugs found during testing.

Handled the review and code merge processes by creating review requests and merge requests using fish eye and git

Developing the webservices Rest calls for SCMCredit and Jpos.

Designing technical design document and process documents for developed application.

Daily work updates to the onsite coordinator & to the clients.

Attended scrum, Bug-Review Meetings.

Project Name: MST BT-ONLINE

Client: Macys Team Size:12

Duration: 18 Months

Environment: Spring, Spring MVC, Java7, Hibernate 3.0, Oracle 11g, Eclipse, Jira, Git.

Description: Macys is using SOCR (Smart order capture reservation) application to deal with POS operations. SOCR internally uses mainframe web services to get various product related information. As a part of the development, we are

developing a complete new set of java webservices to replace existing mainframe web services.

Responsibilities:

Understanding existing SOCR application.

Migration of Legacy APIs written in Mainframe to JAVA and REST APIs.

Implemented different types of controllers, services and facades for the request processing

Developing the Code based on the Design patterns.

Writing well-designed, efficient, and testable code.

Involved in bug fixing.

Responsible for implementing new enhancements and requirements by the client

Developing Restful webservices incorporating authorization and authentication validation for accessing the developed webservices.

Integrating all the webservices with main application.

Implementing log4j for logging into a distinct location

Designing technical design document for developed application

Daily work updates to the onsite coordinator & to the client

Attended Bug-Review Meetings.

Involved in implementation of code review comments from domain engineering team.

Project Name: D2C Macys Active Information Network EA Support.

Client: Macys Team Size: 9

Duration: 7 Months

Environment: UNIX, Shell Scripting, SQL, Tibco BW engine, EMS.

Description: MAIN is Macy's Next-generation Enterprise Managed Real-time Information Platform. MAIN is responsible for providing holistic and cohesive management of core information domains (Product, inventory, Sales, Price, Associate, and Offer) at the speed of business .It helps in exposing a rich set of services, events, and data to support various Omnichannel business needs.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Visveswaraiah Technological University (VTU) in 2014

IT Skills

7,8	2020	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
	2020	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
	7,8	

MicroServices		2020	0 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
SPRING MVC	3.0	2019	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
SERVLETS			
Hibernate and JDBC			
spring boot			
MAVEN			
Git, SVN			
Eclipse			
JIRA			
WebServices- SOAP/REST			
Soap UI, PostMan			
Swagger UI, Putty, WinSCP		2019	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
junit, maven		2020	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
SonarQube, FishEye, SonarLint		2020	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Kannada	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: Middleware Migration

Client: Red Hat

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jun 2020 - Oct 2020 Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 5

Skill Used: Java 8, spring boot, couch db, Rest webservice

Role Description: Java backend developer

Project Details: This project is mainly concentrate on integration between tibco and redhat fuse. As a java backend developer I was responsible for development of multiple modules like tibco projects parsing database migration from mongodb to couch db and part of migration code to fuse XML.

Project Title: Platform Monitor Client: Alcatel-Lucent India Limited Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Jun 2019 - May 2020

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: This project will provide the platform monitor details for the services running for nokia services. Monitor status are provided by Java application which will sync with apache Kafka to get the health status.

Project Title: EPS Enquiry - SCMCredit

Client: Macys Atlanta

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2018 - Mar 2019 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Location: Mysore, India Role: Programmer Team Size: 12

Skill Used: SpringBoot, Java8, GIT Repository, SOAP Web services, Eclipse, Jira, FishEye.

Role Description: 1. Developing the Code based on the client requirements.

2. Writing well-designed, efficient, and testable code.

3.Involved in bug fixing.

4. Worked on code reusability, code coverage, Sonar fixes.

Project Details: EPS Enquiry is an Enterprise Payment Services which is used by 3rd party authorization in Macy's payment services.SCMCredit is an application which integrates with EPS module to provide 3rd party payment service.

The core need of this project is to replace mainframe module with EPS and integration of scmcredit service to Jpos server.

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time